Contact

8801716187302 (Mobile) moinuddin7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/minuddinchowdhury-20464026 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership

WordPress

Codelgniter

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

OCP (Oracle certified Professional)

Minuddin Chowdhury

Sr. Lead Software Engineer at Datahost IT Bangladesh

Summary

I love to work on challenging web applications, love to solve real life problems also love to work on large scale application, system like where real time impact occurs, that will be impacting people instantly. My felicitated programming languages and various tools are PHP, JAVA, C++, Database Optimization, NO sql, Design Pattern, Mapping Data Flow, Analysis business requirements then difine use cases. And love to do software engineering in agile way.

I am a oracle certified professional(OCP) in developer track also Skilled in oracle database and stored programs like function, procedure, trigger etc.

- Have excellent knowledge on MVC architecture.
- Have excellent knowledge on SOLID principle.
- Have excellent knowledge on PHP based open source script.
- Have excellent knowledge on javascript, ajax, jquery, vue js, react js etc.

My expertise are as below,

Language &

Framework:PHP,OOP,Symfony,Laravel,Codeigniter,Cake Php,Zend

CMS: WordPress

Web Technologies: CSS3,Bootstrap,HTML5,JavaScript, JQuery,

JSON, Ajax, Vue JS, Angular, ReactJS

Web Service: REST, SOAP

Databases: Oracle, MySQL

Tools: Netbeans, Sublime, Git, Bitbucket

Project Management Tool: Trello, Wounderlist, Draw.io

Platform: Windows, Linux(Ubuntu)

SDLC: Waterfall, AGILE

Design Patterns: Decorator, Strategy, Dependency Injection, Factory, Facade, Proxy, Adapter, Singleton, Observable, Builder design patterns

Third Party Api: facebook, twitter, google, youtube

Payment Gateway: paypal,sslcommerze,google checkout, strip.

Expertise:

REST api,capable to build Api Service for any third party applications,Build token based api service using O auth 2, Sever Side Push Notification For Android & Ios. Laravel event, notification with pusher as well as with socket.io, scheduling, packaging, console application, helper almost each part of laravel digging deeper part. And I can be capable to work with any kind of php framework as an expert as well as ability to adapt other languages.

Experience

Datahost IT
Sr. Lead Software Engineer
March 2020 - Present (8 months)

House: 82 (3rd floor), Road: 10/1 Block: D, Niketon, Gulshan-1 Dhaka-1212

Website: https://www.datahostbd.com/

Responsibility

Software Requirement analysis, Define use cases, Wireframe, Layout, Coding, follow software design pattern, take care juniors, unit testing and feature testing etc.

About DataHostIT

We are the most reputed web hosting service providing company in Bangladesh. Because, we always provide reliable and affordable services for our clients. We are offering different types of web hosting packages for the favour of our customers. So if you are looking for affordable, reliable and full time supporting web hosting plans, Data Host IT will be your right choice.

Data Host IT is not only providing hosting services but also we are providing software solutions. We are building different types of software solutions for our clients according to their demands. POS Software, School Management Pro, CRM+Project Management, Hospital Management Software, Pharmacy Management Software, Human Resource Management have been developed by our developer team. We can customize these softwares for our clients according to their demands.

We are also providing web design and development services for our clients. We are designing both corporate websites and eCommerce websites. Our another service is bulk SMS service for our customers. We have attractive SMS marketing campaigning plans for different types of businesses. We have updated databases and customized target audiences to send your SMS to your clients or customers.

GrubDealz Restaurant Services Inc. Lead Software Developer June 2016 - Present (4 years 5 months) Regina, Canada

Details: The application has Website, well organized administrative Control Panel, Restaurant Owners Panel, users panel

Website:

GrubDealz Website encompasses showing city wise deal of current day, filter trending deal, filter deals near by you, filter deals higher to lower as well as lower to higher rating, filter deals alphabetically. Showing cuisine type deals, deal type deals, deals of your zone and places, search deals according to any term, deal type, cuisine type as well as restaurant wise etc.

Administrative Panel:

GrubDealz restaurant service administrative panel encompasses entire application planing and management of all activities involved in ACL (Access control), application parameters like deal type, cuisine type, restaurant type, zone, places. Restaurant enroll by google, foursquare and yelp API, then add restaurant details information into GrubDealz database.

Restaurant owners can request to enroll a restaurant using claim request for ownership. GrubDealz management will verify the requested owners if passes enroll the restaurant and allocate the restaurant to the requested owners. Push notification for mobile app.

Restaurant Owners Panel:

Restaurant owners request for ownership by claiming owners request form, claim restaurant have to exist in google or foursquare, GrubDealz management verify owners request, after verification is completed ownership confirmation message with credential link will send owners email, in the panel owner enter their deals, request for more claims, they will manage active deal, pending deal, expired deal and there they will get beautiful dashboard and all the statistics of restaurant and deals.

Users Panel:

GrubDealz provides a panel for the users their user manages their wish deals, delete wish deals, user can register using sign up process of grubdealz, sign up using social authentication like facebook and google.

https://grubdealz.com (Production Server) http://bdfooddeals.com(Develoment)

Better Communication & Automation Ltd.
CTO (Chief Technical Officer) as well as Lead Developer
February 2016 - February 2020 (4 years 1 month)

60, Purana Paltan Line (Level-7) Kustia Zila Somity Bhaban Santinogor, Dhaka-1

Responisbility: Develop software architectural design, define road map, analysis complexity and finding best solutions, reduce pain of development team for gaining functional needs, distribute responsibility to the teams team leader, design an develop API for mobile app and for third party needs.

Better Communication and Automation Ltd. (BCA) provides IT consulting and services to the Public Sector market. We focus our services on Web Development ,Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP), Web Hosting Service, Telecommunication (PABX),CC TV Solution with Device integrated access control system and Business Analytics.

Project:

Survey Management System

Client: NWPC (National Wage and Productive Commission)

Web URL: http://nwpc.gov.bd

Position: Analyst & Lead Application Developer Technology: Codeigniter, MySql, Jquery, Ajx

Design Pattern: Strategy Pattern

Framework: Codeigniter

Details: The survey system has four module, Labor, Trade Union, Industry Owner, desired report from these three parties according to predefined questions taking different type of multiple answers according to that questions. After taking all the answers from various type of people from three sectors (Labor, Trade Union, Industry Owner) automate the application reporting module as of desired format of National Wage and Productive Commission and every and each report comply with 100% various types of statistics methodology.

Integrated Retail Business Management System(SERP)

Project Details:

Position: Analyst & Lead Application Developer

Technology: php, bootstrap, jquery, ajax

Design Pattern: Strategy Pattern, decorator, adopter

Web Service: REST. Framework: Laravel

Integrated Retail Business Management System(SERP) which is suitable for pos, pharmacy, and kind of retail business has 6 modules settings module, receive product, product sales, detail inventory, real life accounts, reports.

http://demopos.bca-bd.com/posapp_v2/ http://nagorikkantha.com (Full functional news site)

Winsock Corporation (PVT Ltd.)
Lead Software Developer
October 2011 - December 2015 (4 years 3 months)
BDBL Bhobon(6 th floor), Kaoran Bazar, Dhaka

Winsock Corporation Private Limited, a member of BASIS, and working in Bangladesh for over a decade in the fields of Software Development, Automation, and ICT development satisfying the needs of both our

Governmental and private sector organizations globally. Our moto is to increase productivity and efficiency of organization as well as organizational workforce using the leverage of ICT. It has been a journey of successful development as the client base has gotten stronger and more dependent on our product and services.

Company website http://winsockcorp.com/

Project:

Enterprise solutions for SAIC

Client: SAIC

Organization URL: http://www.simt.edu.bd/

Position: Lead Application Developer Technology: PHP, MySql, Jquery, Ajax

Design Pattern: Strategy Pattern, singleton, adopter

Details: ERP has 13 Modules like students enrollment, Exam, Result, Library, Schedule(routine), Inventory, HR, Payroll, Account(student & organizational), Students portal, Teachers panel, Administrative panel, result, result published, and All desired reports including poly technique formatted tabulation sheet.

Clinic Management System

Client: Foresight Prenatal Clinic Bonani

Organization URL: https://foresightprenatal.com/

Position: Lead Application Developer Technology: PHP, MySql, Jquery, Ajax

Design Pattern: Strategy Pattern, singleton, adopter

Details: Clinic management system has 4 modules patient enrollment, billing, inventory and accounts module. All module are integrated all around.

Reunion event management

Client: ORWA (Old remians welfare association)
Organization URL: https://foresightprenatal.com/

Position: Lead Application Developer

Technology: PHP, Zend, MySql, Jquery, Ajax Design Pattern: Strategy Pattern, adopter

Details: The reunion event management software enroll their members, registere their members for the events, generate donation bill.

infobase limited Senior Software Engineer April 2008 - November 2010 (2 years 8 months)

29 Subash Bose Avenue Luxmibazar , 55/B Purana Paltan, Dhaka - 1000

INFOBASE are one of the leading digital agencies working since 2002. INFOBASE have been designing and developing digital communication for all sectors. Our team of specialists works passionately and collaboratively on digital solutions – from websites to mobile concepts and eCommerce to mCommerce. Our goal is to create high-quality, digital communication that makes an impact.

We have expertise in creating bespoke, innovative and user focused solutions that transform customer experiences across the digital landscape.

Working at INFOBASE as a senior software engineer to develop websites based on client need and web application like sales & inventory, accounting, pos etc.

Bangladesh Air Force Software Developer January 2007 - March 2008 (1 year 3 months) Kurmitola, Dhaka

The Bangladesh Air Force (Bangladesh Biman Bahini in Bangla), is the air arm of the Bangladesh Armed Forces. The embryo of Bangladesh Air Force (BAF) was formed on 28 September 1971 during the war of Liberation with only three aircraft. During last 43 years Bangladesh Air Force (BAF) has been developed as one of the advanced and capable air force of the world.

http://www.baf.mil.bd

Working at BAF as a core developer of their warehouse inventory management system, under a third party software company simens, during my service period I was develop a module called part number management module of their various parts and machine tools. And it has developed by oracle developer 6i, report 6i, database 8i.

Development Environment Dev 6i, Report 6i

Database

Oracle 8i

Globe Pharmaceutical Group of Companies Ltd Software Developer

August 2005 - January 2007 (1 year 6 months)

Alipur, Begomgonj, Noakhali

I was working their as a core developer during my service period I was develop their sales & inventory management system. And it has developed by oracle developer 6i, report 6i, database 8i.

Development Environment Dev 6i, Report 6i

Database

Oracle 8i

Education

Asian University of Bangladesh

B.Sc (Engg) in computer science & Engineering, Computer science & Engineering · (2001 - 2005)